JAMES WOLFE



Wolfe.James.J96@gmail.com (703)789-0919 Northern Virginia Website Portfolio







SUMMARY

Computer Science graduate with a passion for problem-solving and learning, demonstrated experience in computer troubleshooting and customer service. Developed technical skill sets required to thrive in a professional work environment such as hardware repair, Linux, and

SKILLS

- **AWS Cloud Services** RedHat Software Troubleshooting Hardware Troubleshooting
- HTML & CSS Java SSH Visual Studio Code

PROJECTS

Headless Media Center

Achieved assembling a media center using a Raspberry Pi 4 by mounting Volumio OS to the device, making a blue-tooth hotspot available for connection.

Established Computer System

- Strategized and executed a computer system set up and debugged hardware and software issues.
- Showed my skills reseating CMOS and accurately aligning memory when the system did not POST and had temperature issues.

Website Financial Dashboard with Arrays GitHub Repository

- Devised an EC2 static website and implemented ApexCharts with Java arrays to create a financial dashboard.
- Utilized services such as, Visual Studio Code, AWS Cloud, WinSCP, and GitHub to develop the project.

Static Website Portfolios GitHub Repository

Coded four HTML, CSS, and Java-Script website templates by uploading the files to database and publishing services like S3, Azure Container, Surge, and GitHub Pages.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Woodworker Sue's Antiques

06/2021 — Present

Planned refurbishing projects for 18th and 19th century antique furniture involving sanding and staining utilizing attention to detail.

Data Technician CORESTAFF SERVICES

11/2020 - 12/2020

- Accomplished hardware-focused AWS Cloud troubleshooting tickets involving unable to POST and vital updates.
- Adapted problem-solving skills to debug malfunctioning servers by rebooting servers or reseating and replacing hardware and cables.

Restaurant Server Mariachis TequliaRia & Restaurant

06/2018 - 01/2019

Served customers while multi-tasking food orders, drink and chip refills, and station clean-up in a fast-paced environment.

Sale's Associate PetValu

09/2015 - 08/2017

Faced with pet nutritional and health related issues I asked questions involving diet, exercise, symptoms, and allergies to accurately solve customer concern and did it effectively by utilizing critical thinking and communication skills.

CERTIFICATIONS

AWS Cloud Practitioner - 7BEZSG02PNEEQ83D

Agile Scrum Fundamentals - ude.my/UC-800faeff-a669-4e5b-b802-3cbb834cdd2f

Linux Administration Bootcamp - ude.my/UC-fcd5c324-ad8c-4b70-a83d-b9712cb3b0f8

EDUCATION

Computer Science, Northern Virginia Community College 2016 — 2020

Worked on the fundamentals on computers and how they function, practice coding in Java, HTML, and CSS, and worked through mathematical problems involving algebraic and transcendental formulas.